Guide to the Washington State Vassar Club Records, 1909-1956 (bulk 1945-1957)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Washington State Vassar Club Records
1909-1957
1945-1957
Washington State Vassar Club
0.6 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials relating to the creation and subsequent activities of the Washington State Vassar Club.
Administrative History
Small groups of Vassar College Alumnae living in the Seattle began meeting informally as early as 1906, but it wasn't until 1945 that The Puget Sound Vassar Club was formed. The club is still active but is now known as the Washington State Vassar Club.
Scope and Content Note
The Washington State Vassar Club Records contain the club's constitution, correspondence, mailing lists and meeting minutes. The bulk of the collection is from the years the group was known as the Puget Sound Vassar Club. Also included is a register from the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, which was held in the summer of 1909. Although the register was apparently meant to be a list of Vassar alumnae who attended the exposition, many people with no connection to the college added their signatures.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition (1909: Seattle, Wash.)
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Societies and clubs
VCL Categories
Vassar College Alumnae/I Organizations
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, 12 Mar 2009
Acquisition Information
The Puget Sound Vassar Club Records were a gift of Jane T. Merritt (VC 1981), June 1992.
Container List
- Constitution, 1945 (Folder 1.1)
- Vassar Club Handbooks and other general AAVC material, 1942-1955 (Folder 1.2)
- Minutes (with a note about Club's History), 1945-1957 (Folder 1.3)
- Correspondence, 1945-1957 (Folder 1.4)
- Mailings to Members, 1945-1955 (Folder 1.5)
- Membership Correspondence, 1945-1955 (Folder 2.1)
- Financial Records, 1945-1956 (Folder 2.2)
- Foreign Alumnae Assistance, ca. 1948 (Folder 2.3)
- Mailing Lists (Folder 2.4)
- Holly Lists (Folder 2.5)
- Northwest Products (Folder 2.6)
- Cooking School (Folder 2.7)
- "Vassar Register" from the Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, 1909 (Box 3)